KACPER KULA

SENIOR JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER





hello@kulak.at



medium.com/@kulak



Hello! I am Kacper, Senior JavaScript Developer from Warsaw, Poland. I am planning to move to London, UK at the beginning of 2019 and I'm seeking new opportunities there. Throughout my 10 years long professional career I have held various positions ranging from being Senior Developer, Product Developer, taking partial responsibility of a Project Manager and a Team Leader to becoming Developer Evangelist. I apply myself fully in everything I'm doing.

I first got interested in programming and software engeneering when I was 10 years old and it has been my passion ever since.

I'm always trying to hone my skills and stay up to date with my profession. Besides work I often participate in various meetings, hackathons and devote time to my personal projects.

I can send recommendation letter from my recent employee on request.

EXPERIENCE

SwingDev

2018.03 - 2018.08 Developer Evangelist

In this new role in the company which I had build myself. Among others, I improved the recruitment process, popularised technologies and solutions used within company through many articles and a conference, conducting workshops and creating internal developer guide.

writing articles, conducting interviews, creating developer guide, conducting workshops, creating and managing business relations

2014.08 - 2018.03 Senior JavaScript Developer

I have been maintaining and ameliorating existing applications as well as creating new solutions from the ground up. Engaging in responsibilities of Project Manager, Team Lead and Senior Architect and mentoring Junior Developers.

JavaScript, Node.js, PostgreSQL, Redis, Docker, Webpack, AWS, React, Angular, TypeScript, Agile

WhoElse

2014.04 - 2014.07 Android Developer

Developing Android application with 50k+ userbase.

Android, Java

John Pitcher Interactive

2013 - 2014.03 Web & Mobile Developer

Creating various landing pages, sites and online contests mostly for marketing campaings and the government.

Silex, Node.js, Android, PhoneGap, Grunt

JavaScript, Backbone.js, PHP

Junior PHP / JavaScript Developer

Creating Facebook embeded sites, mailings.

PHP5, MySQL, MongoDB, JavaScript, HTM5, CSS3, Facebook API, Google Maps API

Confected.com

2011 - 2013 Product Developer

Conference management and engagement mobile platform. Used by TEDxWarsaw and Imperial College

PHP, Zend Framework, MySQL, HTML5, Agile, Mobile, RWD

Various Companies

2007 - 2014 Freelancer

Web development (frontend, backend) for various companies.

PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Backbone.js, Android

NON-PROFIT ORGANISATIONS

Girls.js 2017 - now

Tutor (voulenteer)

Teaching women basics of JavaScript on one-day-long workshops regular series.

Fenix Foundation 2015 - 2017

Cofounder / Director of Computer Science Department

Cofounded foundation for the best High School students, teaching them physics and computer science beyond schools programme. Responsible for organizing and managing Computer Science department, finding and onboarding teachers, scheduling and promoting lectures.

Great Orchestra of Christmas Charity

2009 - now

Peace Patrol member (voulenteer)

Volunteering in the biggest annual charity fundraising and on Woodstock Festival.

EDUCATION

University of Warsaw

2013 - 2014

Computer Science

Dropped on the second year.

LANGUAGES

Polish - native speaker

English - C1

HOBBIES

Retro and modern gaming

Arduino / Electronics

Music creation

ACHIEVEMENTS / AWARDS

HackArt by Polish National Museum

3rd place

Mind the Art project - AR solution for museums.

Canon Hackathon

3rd place

MusicMapper - Wall mapping solution for visualzing music using image projectors and Fast Fourier Transform.

Allegro Hackathon

2015

2018

2018

1st place

Allegrator - mobile app recommending you geek products based on your gaming and music history.

Dice+ Hackathon

2014

3rd place

Android game to be used with hardware bluetooth dice.

Google Glass Hackathon

2013

2nd place

Shopping list application for Google Glass.

Google Hackathon

2011

Award of Distinction

HTML5 game with geolocation capabilities.